<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog | Ananya Tadepalli – Professional Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/media/icon_hu_982c5d63a71b2961.png</url>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Crypto Wave: Catch It Wisely</title>
      <link>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/crypto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“ Risk comes from not knowing what you’re doing&amp;quot; - Warren Buffett&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of the US Presidential elections have sparked a new rally for crypto-related shares like Bitcoin, Dogecoin, Coinbase, and MicroStrategy. As this bull run draws more investors into the crypto market, it&amp;rsquo;s important to revisit the risks posed by cryptocurrency security threats. These risks are not just real—they can be financially catastrophic for those who fail to understand them. 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Cybersecurity Awareness to Awakening</title>
      <link>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/cybersecurity-awareness-to-awakening/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/cybersecurity-awareness-to-awakening/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world where cyber warfare and hacktivists are on the rise, personal cybersecurity becomes all the more important. Hello, my name is Ananya! I am a senior at Innovation Academy pursuing the IT and Cybersecurity pathways. In recent months, we have witnessed alarming cyber incidents, from the targeting of Atlanta airport by pro-Russian hacktivists to disruptions in the Fulton County School District. We are at a pivotal moment because our traditional security views are colliding with the reality of cyber warfare of the 21st century—join me as I discuss how these crossroads can lead us to a safer, more secure tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watch the full TEDx talk here: 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bluetooth Alert: Cybersecurity in the Wireless Realm</title>
      <link>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/bluetooth-alert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/bluetooth-alert/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Intel, “over 4.7 billion Bluetooth® devices were shipped in 2021. As one of the most common wireless connectivity standards in the world, Bluetooth technology plays an integral part in everyday life.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bluetooth technology has revolutionized communication since its development in the 1990’s by Dutch engineer, Dr. Jaap Haarsten. It allows devices to communicate with each other without supporting network infrastructure such as a wireless router or access point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, individuals predominantly employ Bluetooth technology to establish connections between various devices, including wireless headphones, keyboards, mice, and speakers, with both personal computers and mobile devices. This communication is facilitated through short-range radio frequency connections, allowing various devices equipped with Bluetooth to interact within a specified distance.    
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Staying Quantum Safe</title>
      <link>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/quantum-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/quantum-safe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 13th, 2024, NIST announced the first three post-quantum cryptography (PQC) standards after 8 years of research into techniques to guard against data breaches using Quantum Computers. Cryptography has always been shrouded in mystery and intrigue; hence I began this blog to answer some common questions, with the intent of increasing adoption by de-mystifying.   
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware of GenAI Hallucinations</title>
      <link>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/gen-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/gen-ai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, for a team meeting, I was looking for a trivia question and asked ChatGPT, “How many sports will be played in the Paris Olympics 2024?” The unequivocal answer it gave was 32 and it even listed all 32 of them. But if we go to the Olympics.com, the committee will provide a list of 40 sports.  What just happened was a hallucination. ChatGPT did not have all of the details about the latest Olympics, so it assumed old data was correct and provided a confident answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The thing that I try to caution people the most is what we call the ‘hallucinations problem’,” Sam Altman, CEO of OpenAI, told ABC News. “The model will confidently state things as if they were facts entirely made up.&amp;quot; he continued.   
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Home Internet of Things: Connecting You to the World</title>
      <link>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/home-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/home-iot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Internet of Things&amp;rdquo; refers to a vastly augmented network of interconnected devices that gather and exchange data over the internet to make lives easier. Ranging from simple sensors to complex systems, these devices can be installed at home, workplaces, or cities. IoT has formed a significant part of our daily life and appears in different forms such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Home thermostat to lighting and security can be monitored and controlled by a person using their smartphone, ensuring the best energy usage and peace of mind.
Wearable devices, from fitness trackers to smartwatches, track health metrics, providing incentives to live more healthily by monitoring daily activities, sleep patterns, and heart rates.
In the kitchen, smart devices work to simplify meal preparation and management—many of them interface with virtual assistants like Amazon Alexa or Google Assistant.
Modern cars are equipped with smart sensors, through which it can be diagnosed in real time on its performance, navigation, and autonomous driving.   
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Cyber Risk Assessment Tool</title>
      <link>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/p-crat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ananyasai.github.io/portfolio/blog/p-crat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“ Risk comes from not knowing what you’re doing&amp;quot; - Warren Buffett&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his book “Born to Run”, Christopher McDougall writes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Every morning in Africa, a gazelle wakes up. It knows it must run faster than the fastest lion or it will be killed. Every morning a lion wakes up. It knows it must outrun the slowest gazelle or it will starve to death. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether you&amp;rsquo;re a lion or gazelle. When the sun comes up, you&amp;rsquo;d better be running.&amp;rdquo;
Today in the Cyber-world there is similar desperate race for survival, where we are all facing the predicament of the Gazelle, while hackers are searching for their next victim. Fortunately for us we don’t have to be better than the best hacker, rather it is enough for us be better than other targets.  
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
